Good to see you!
A NIGHTMARE STAINED IN BLACK
Here to pick up that
Conjuring Ink you ordered?
[WITCH] Yes. Thank you
for getting it in so quickly!
Also, there's
a crack in my wand.
Think you could fix it for me?
[TARTAH] That flash of light
was blinding.
There's no way Granda
could've missed it.
Perhaps Mr. Qifrey knows
the real reason Granda forgot.
Or perhaps he is the reason.
[wind blowing]
[Coco whimpers]
- Oh, no! I'm sorry!
- [Qifrey grunting]
I'm so sorry! Are you all right?
I'm so sorry!
[QIFREY] Seems that
Grasping Wind seal
wasn't quite right.
Perhaps a bit too large
for grabbing a mountain apple.
I agree, the smaller one
only made them wobble,
so I thought
I'd try making it stronger,
but I guess I overcorrected.
[TETIA] How about giving
the Sign of Pulling
a little twist, like that?
I mean, you twist an apple
when you pick it, right?
[QIFREY] Clever thought!
Adapting the sign to the goal.
That is what makes magic
versatile.
When you fail, try to determine
the reason for your failure.
And when you succeed,
ask why it worked.
That trial-and-error process
is what makes
repeating lessons valuable!
We mustn't act thoughtlessly
out of habit, right, Master?
Couldn't have said it better.
You're an excellent teacher,
Master Tetia.
[Tetia exclaims]
Did Master Qifrey
just call me Master?
[squeals] I'm blushing! Stop!
But not really, you're welcome
to keep going if you--
[ALL] Uh?
[AGOTT] Are you in any position
to be instructing others?
If you know
what it takes to improve,
then perhaps
you should do so yourself.
[Tetia and Coco chuckle softly]
[TETIA] Right, then! I'm ready!
- Show me how it's done!
- [Coco laughs]
[AGOTT] That wasn't meant
to sound like an invitation!
- I have a test to study for.
- [overlapping chatter]
You can't expect me
to waste my time...
- [thuds]
- [Qifrey laughs]
[birds chirping]
[COCO] So the test I took
in the Dadah Range
is the first test
of several, right?
- [RICHEH] Yes.
- [ALL] Huh?
A total of five stupid tests
that don't matter.
As if such drivel
helps you draw.
[QIFREY] The tests mean
to teach you about yourself
by challenging you.
How much they matter or not
is dependent upon
the attitude of the taker.
Still, I acknowledge
that it can be difficult
to enjoy something you aren't
taking part in by choice.
It's an issue
that even the witches of old
struggled with.
"Magic exists
to bring people happiness.
To make our apprentices suffer
would violate that ideal."
The Three Wise Ones
considered this,
and devised tests that people
would want to take.
Thrilling adventures
in the outside world!
♪
[QIFREY] The first test,
the Consent of the Crown.
"To earn the permission
to become an apprentice."
Second,
the Sincerity of the Shield.
"To walk beside
your master with devotion."
Third, the Query
of the Qui Vive.
"To prove your path worthy,
and take up the key."
Fourth, the Goodwill
of Her Grace.
"To grant a wish,
and stand alone."
Finally, the Words of the Wise.
"To now become
the teacher yourself."
These make up
the Pentacle of Proving.
With each forward step
you take on this path,
you're allowed to do more
with your magic.
Pass the fourth test,
and you're a full-fledged witch,
- no longer in need of tutelage.
- [Tetia chuckles softly]
[QIFREY] Pass the third test,
and you may take on
the Tower of Tomes.
[QIFREY]
The last test entitles you
to take on apprentices.
No need to think about that one
until after you graduate.
Really? But what if we want to?
I think about life
after graduation all the time!
So much fun.
Traveling to far-off places,
helping everyone
I can with my magic,
hearing "thank you" from people
all over the world.
What a treat!
This person does the thanking,
and that person gets thanked!
One spell of gratitude,
two happy people!
Nothing could be better
than that, no way!
Two birds, one stone!
Two needs, one deed!
Happiness comes in twos,
just like pigtails!
Another reason
I'm excited to grow up is
so I can design myself a cap
with two points on top!
Who knew your hair had
so much meaning?
You do get to choose
your own cap
when you're
a full-fledged witch, it's true.
[RICHEH]
I think tests are the worst.
[COCO] Huh?
[RICHEH] They're annoying.
I hate being told what to do,
and made to draw spells
I don't want to draw.
[AGOTT] If you only draw
the spells you want to...
you'll be stuck,
unable to learn anything new.
[wind blowing]
[RICHEH] That's fine with me.
If being an adult
means being forced
to do things
you don't want to do,
then I'd rather stay as I am.
I'm going inside.
Oh, Richeh.
[AGOTT] Not me.
I refuse to stay
the way I am now.
There are too many things
beyond my reach.
I'll get through the tests
as quickly as possible.
And then,
I'll become a librarian
in the Tower.
Why does growing up
have to happen so slowly?
[COCO] Huh?
[TETIA] Agott comes
from a long line of witches,
descended from an apprentice
to the Three Wise Ones.
The head is always a librarian.
What was it called?
House Arklaum, I think.
[COCO] So Agott wants to get
to the Tower of Tomes as well.
[TETIA] And you?
What kind of witch
would you like to become, Coco?
[COCO] Well, my journey started
in a different place than yours.
My path is laid out for me.
Anyway, for now,
I should probably focus
on learning more spells!
All right!
Let's give that
Grasping Wind spell
- one more shot!
- [TETIA] Hurrah!
[QIFREY] The drawing of spells
helps you to remember them,
which in turn, grants you
the power to use them.
[overlapping chatter]
[QIFREY] Power thus acquired
will never betray you.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[Coco gasps softly]
Everyone? Where'd you go?
And it's so dark.
It's not night already, is it?
- [COCO'S MOM] Coco.
- [gasps]
- [COCO'S MOM] Coco!
Coco...
[Coco breathes shakily]
[Coco cries] Mom!
Mom! I'm sorry!
It's all my fault.
I just couldn't give up
on magic,
but I never meant to hurt you!
[COCO'S MOM]
And yet, I warned you, didn't I?
Normal people can't use magic.
[Coco breathes shakily] Mom?
[AGOTT] You ignorant Outsider.
Look at all the damage
you've done.
Turning your mother to stone.
Putting those around you
in danger.
But it's fine, because
you didn't "mean to," did you?
[OLRUGGIO]
We'll have nothing to do
with the Brimmed Caps here.
[TARTAH]
There are certain things
that certain people
just can't do.
[EASTHIES]
Exceptions cannot be allowed.
[QIFREY]
It was all kept a secret
to prevent tragedies like this.
[Coco gasps]
[Coco screams]
Behold what your avarice
for magic has wrought...
You are to blame.
As you will be
when the world falls apart!
- [shattering]
- [Coco gasps]
[Coco breathes shakily]
[Coco breathes heavily]
[brushbuddy squeaks]
- [footsteps]
- [Qifrey gasps]
Oh, Master.
You're still awake?
[AGOTT]
I wanted to keep working.
[QIFREY] Work wisely,
and honor your limits.
Right. Off to bed.
[AGOTT]
You're awake, too, are you?
[COCO] Yes.
I had trouble sleeping.
I see.
[scribbling]
[COCO]
Drawing helps you remember,
which grants you power.
How much more drawing
will I have to do...
before I can save my mom?
[insects trilling]
[QIFREY] So long now.
So very long.
So long have I waited
for this day.
When the
Three Wise Ones forbade
the casting of spells
upon the body,
the Righteous Witches
of Healingcraft,
who used their magic
to heal the body,
fought them on it
to the bitter end.
Their Twinned Bottles spell
which allowed them to share
medicine among them,
was lost to the world
when their memories were taken.
This spell allowed
the contents of a vial
even a great distance away
to be transferred to another
through a seal-inscribed medal,
so the concoctions they needed
would always be accessible.
A delicate instrument
of healing
lost since the Day of the Pact.
Lost, ironically, to all
but the Brimmed Caps.
A beautiful spell,
but I must dissect you,
for you are the only connection
I have to them.
I won't touch
the Conjuring Ink yet.
It's too dangerous a mystery.
The item I need
is the inscribed medal
hiding away inside the vial.
But can I remove it
without being detected?
That medal is tied to them.
Were I but to place it
inside a Guidance Orb,
its components, its owner,
where it was made...
every detail of its existence
would point toward them.
The tiniest of hints...
leading the way
to the greatest of discoveries.
[Qifrey grunts]
[QIFREY] A lightning spell?
I'm caught already!
[QIFREY] Huh?
Water? No!
[QIFREY] I was too careless.
I can't use spells underwater.
♪
[Qifrey coughing]
[gasps, continues coughing]
[Qifrey breathes shakily]
[breathes heavily] You're here.
The one with the eye.
[Qifrey breathes heavily]
No.
Not yet.
I still have to...
[Qifrey breathes shakily]
Damn it.
I won't give up.
I will get back
what was taken from me.
[coin clinks]
[WITCH] After all that trouble
to give it to her...
[grunts] What a shame.
[birds chirping]
[both yawning]
Uh? Synchronized yawns!
You keep doing that.
Why? Were you two up all night?
[Coco yawns]
A-ha! Every evening,
both of you transform
into magic knights
and do battle with your foes!
[AGOTT] Transformation spells
are forbidden.
And yawning all day proves
nothing more remarkable
than a need for more sleep.
These last several nights,
you've been staying up late
to practice, haven't you?
[Coco yawns, chuckles]
It's true, guess something
about the night
makes me feel inspired.
[TETIA] You can't do that, Coco!
I understand, but you shouldn't
push yourself too hard!
[RICHEH] Good magic
starts with good sleep.
And good food.
Master Olly says so, too!
[OLRUGGIO] If you don't get
good sleep in your youth,
you'll pay for it
in your old age.
True!
I'll brew some erbe tea
to help get you to sleep!
Want some, Master?
[Qifrey groaning]
- [TETIA] Master?
- [Qifrey gasps]
Uh, what were you saying?
My apologies, I took a few bites
and suddenly felt sleepy.
Leave the tea to me!
- Hot!
- [all gasp]
[shattering]
[TETIA] Master, are you sure
you're all right?
[QIFREY] Yes, quite fine.
I'm still numb
from the lightning.
But I'm afraid
my slippery fingers
have ruined
the last of our erbe tea.
I'll go out and pick
some more leaves.
Work on your Primers
while I'm gone, everyone.
Oh, and leave the mess,
I'll tidy it up later!
[all groan softly]
Master's acting strange, right?
Sleep deprivation
is a very serious affliction.
[COCO] Huh?
[TETIA] I'll make him drink
- that erbe tea tonight.
- [COCO] That's right.
- [TETIA] He needs some rest!
- [COCO] Agott...
- could I talk to you?
- [indistinct chatter]
[COCO] Here.
The Sylph Shoes you borrowed.
[COCO] I'm sorry for taking
so long to return them.
Getting the seal just right
was no simple task.
Is this what you were
working on last night?
[COCO] Ah, yes.
Though I'm sure any of you
could have done a lot better.
If they're hard to fly with,
feel free to redraw them.
[AGOTT] What's all this about?
What are you plotting, exactly?
I'm confused.
The first test...
The Dadah Range,
the Diadem Herb...
I was the one
who forced you to take it,
and yet, you never revealed that
to Master Qifrey.
Nor to our Watchful Eye,
though you had every chance.
And now,
after protecting me like that,
you've even fixed
my Sylph Shoes.
For what reason?
What are you trying
to accomplish?
I don't understand you.
[Coco gasps softly]
That day...
you did force me
to take the test.
I felt alone,
and I was so frightened.
I could have chosen to sit
and wait for someone to come.
But...
Instead, I stood
at the base of those mountains,
and I decided that I would try.
It was me.
I'm the one who wanted
to prove I could do it.
I wanted to overcome the trial
with my own magic
and feel like
things weren't hopeless.
Because if I couldn't...
[AGOTT]
So what are you telling me?
That I've been dwelling on it
all this time for no reason?
That's just...
- [thuds]
- [Agott gasps]
- [AGOTT] Coco!
- [Coco breathes heavily]
[birds chirping]
Good, the feeling's coming back.
I wonder if they noticed.
They're smart children,
so it's possible.
If this gets out, it's all over.
I can't allow that to happen.
You'll keep my secret.
Won't you, Puffpuff?
Uh? You don't much care
for the name, then?
[brushbuddy squeaks]
[QIFREY] Oh, I thought it was
rather charming myself.
"Puffpuff."
Perhaps not.
[AGOTT] Master!
Agott! Goodness,
you gave me a fright!
You were going so fast there!
That's because
the signs are too long,
and it's throwing
the Casting Seal off balance!
Oh, really? Shall I have a look?
[AGOTT] No, not right now!
There's an emergency! It's Coco!
[Qifrey gasps]
[QIFREY] We're off
to the hospital in Kalhn.
[OLRUGGIO] Go.
I'll watch the atelier.
[QIFREY] Thanks.
If you girls need anything,
Olly's here for you.
Hold on, Coco.
Hospital's not far.
The fever's getting worse.
She needs to see a doctor soon!
[bell tolling]
[laughter]
- All right, it's my turn!
- Don't mess it up!
[BOY 1] There!
[BOY 2] I've got you now!
What? Aww...
The idea was to catch it.
Oh, hey, Tartah,
where are you going?
Sorry. About time for me
to catch the ferry.
[BOY 1] Ah, right.
[BOY 2] You live on the sandbar,
don't you?
Why the ferry?
If you're from a witch family,
then wouldn't it be easier
for you to just fly?
[BOY 2] Good point.
Well, because, uh...
because those are the rules!
[boy 1 groans]
See you tomorrow, then!
- Right. So long!
- Bye!
[running footsteps]
[TARTAH] People who know little
always have a lot to say.
I would love to fly home
if I could.
- [Tartah gasps]
- [Qifrey pants]
[TARTAH]
Oh, Mr. Qifrey, it's you.
What are you doing--
[QIFREY] Tartah, can you show me
the way to the hospital?
I don't know this area well.
Ah! The hospital? Here!
- There's a shortcut.
- [QIFREY] Thank you.
♪
[both panting]
[TARTAH] Wait.
- [Tartah pants]
- [QIFREY] Thank you.
Of course,
she'll be well cared for.
Wait here, if you would.
[Tartah panting]
[QIFREY]
I hope she'll be all right.
Thank you for your help, Tartah.
What luck you were here
to lead me.
It's nothing to speak of, I--
Oh, no, it certainly is.
Clearly, you're quite
an observant young man.
You must look at things
very carefully.
[Tartah gasps]
[TARTAH] Say, Mr. Qifrey...
You know, since you're here,
I have something to ask you.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
EPISODE 10: A PROMISE IN SILVER